you guys this looks like a fun one one
over one plus one over one plus one over
x equals 420 over 834. so for the first
step we want to do this one plus one
over X in order to give them a common
denominator we're going to multiply this
one on the left hand side by X over x
and x over x times 1 is just X over X
and now that they have a common
denominator we can write them as a
single fraction so it becomes X plus one
over X so now let's focus on this right
here this is basically saying 1 divided
by X Plus 1 over X the division of a
fraction is the same thing as
multiplying by the reciprocal so if we
change this divide into a multiply we
can flip this fraction and one times
this is just this so we want to rewrite
this whole thing as X over X plus one
now let's get rid of this stuff next we
want to add these together and we need
to give this a common denominator with
this so we're going to multiply this one
by X Plus 1 over X plus one well this
times 1 is just this thing and now that
these two fractions have a common
denominator we can write them as a
single fraction so all we did was add
the numerators and last X Plus X is
equal to 2 x with this right here we're
doing the division thing again we're
doing one divided by this fraction down
here anytime you do that we can change
the Divide to a multiply and flip the
fraction and then one times something is
just the something so now we want to
rewrite this entire left side as this
fraction right here or in other words
you can think of it as bringing this X
Plus 1 to the top now let's get rid of
this stuff I'm noticing on the side we
can simplify this fraction both the top
and the bottom are divisible by six on
top 420 divided by 6 is 70. and on
bottom made 34 divided by 6 is 139. in
order to solve this proportion Let's
cross multiply we have the 139 times X
plus one equals 70 times 2x plus 1 and
then if we distribute 139 times x is
139x 139 times 1 is 139 70 times 2x is
140x and 70 times 1 is 70. now we have
an x on both sides so let's subtract
139x from both sides these cancel so on
the left hand side we only have 139 and
on the right hand side 140x minus 139x
is just X now we still have the plus 70.
now on the left hand side 139 minus 70
is 69. nice that is the answer to our
question so we can put a box around it
how exciting